Hello friends, I am Dr. Ved Prakash
Mishra, welcome to my YouTube channel.
Today I will tell you about the disease that occurs in the
area between the anus and the genitals.  The
disease is called Forestier's gangrene.
What happens in Foreignnier Gangrene is that the tissue
from the anus to the penium region up to the scrotum
suddenly starts
rotting due to infection.  There is a greater possibility of this happening due to dirt, drinking alcohol,
injury or in
people who are diabetic.
What happens in this is that suddenly there is a little redness,
then gradually the swelling increases
and very soon a wound starts forming in it
and all the flesh there starts rotting.
This process happens so fast that the
patient is unable to understand.  By the time
he understands in a day or two, the entire disease
spreads.  If there is sugar then it spreads more rapidly.  The
reason given for this is
bacterial infection. It is said that
this happens due to infection of many bacteria like anaerobic bacteria
and it slowly damages the tissue.  The
entire area, the perineum
area, starts rotting,
starts stinking and the patient is in danger.
His life becomes in danger.   There is only
one way for the patient to treat this.
He should be operated upon.  If there is a diabetic
patient, then first of all it is necessary to control the sugar
and whatever area has become dead or started
rotting, the entire
area is removed through surgery, which is removed from the flesh,
then regular dressing is done,
good antibiotics are given, some
strong medicines are given, there are
medicines for wound formation and the most important thing is to
dress it properly, it gets
cured slowly by dressing it and medicines.  Sometimes the funnel gangrene may
also be connected to the patient's anal canal.  So this creates a kind
of fistula.  Fun Gangun is
creating a fistula whose connection
remains inside.  So what we do in that is we
surgically remove all the bad tissue outside and we put a cast
in the lower part which is connected to the anal canal.
First the
outer part fills up slowly.  When the
outer part is filled, the buttermilk is
slowly tightened.  It is changed weekly
and the cystula also has to be treated along with it.
So if you ever feel
that this area is the perineum area which is basically the
area between the latrine passage and the scrotum.  If swelling or redness is seen in it,
then immediately contact any of your anorectal
surgeons and
get it treated immediately.  If it is not treated on time then
it is a fatal disease.
If you
want to go for any such disease then contact on the number given below.
[music]